Guide to the National Grange of the Patrons of Husbandry records, 1842-1994
National Grange of the Patrons of Husbandry records, 1842-1994
- Series X. Director of Youth Activities, Wib Justi
  - Transport and Travel Contractors, Inc., 1954, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    Correspondence, memo, note, instruction, tickets. Includes German Rural Teen-ager Project, John Ricksen.
  - "U" Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1950-1963 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - The United Christian Youth Movement, 1952, 1955, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    Includes John S. Wood, National Citizenship Seminar.
  - UNICEF, 1957, 1959, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    Correspondence, note. Includes Adele Wallace, United States Committee for UNICEF.
  - United Nations Tours - N.Y.C., 1953-1955 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    Correspondence, application, information related to U.N. Tour - German Rural Teenager Project.
  - United States Advisory Commission., 1951-1960 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    Correspondence, comments, suggestions, diary excerpts. Includes Harold E. Howland, J. L. Morrill, International Information Administration and United States Advisory Commission on Educational Exchange, Department of State.
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1956-1964 (Box 29, Folder 34 (a, b))
    Correspondence, note, form, chart, memo, release, summary, statement. Includes Alta Peck, Cannon C. Hearne, Home Economics Committee (N.G.), Foreign Agricultural Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture.
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1958-1962 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    Correspondence, program, biographies. Material on Youth Planning Committee (1960 White House Conference on Children and Youth), Vocational Agriculture (conference). Includes A. W. Tenney, Agricultural Education Branch, Office of Education, Department of HEW.
  - U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Standards, 1955-1964 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    Correspondence, draft, article, list, photograph. Includes Evelyn Murray, Louise Q. Blodgett, Bureau of Employment Security and Bureau of Labor Standards, U.S. Department of Labor.
  - U.S. Information, 1957-1960, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    Correspondence, presentation from Farm Committee. Includes Jane E. Boyle, Office of Private Cooperation, United States Information Agency.
  - U.S. State Department - Houlihan, Marita, 1952-1955, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 38 (a, b))
    Correspondence, questions and answers, analysis, applications for International Rural Teenager Project. Includes James B. Parker, Marita Houlihan, International Education Exchange Service and International Information Administration, Department of State.
  - "V" Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1955-1962 (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - "WYZ" Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1950-1964 (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - World Affairs Center - correspondence, 1955, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - World Neighbors, Inc. - Peters, John L., 1954-1961 (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - World Wide Games - Correspondence, 1955, 1959-1963 (Box 29, Folder 43)
- Series XI. Books, Journals, Articles
  - Wyatt D. Aiken. The Grange: Its Origin, Progress, and Educational Purposes. An address, 1883, with annotations. Philadelphia: J. A. Wagenseller., 1884 (Box 30)
  - Wyatt D. Aiken. The Grange: Its Origin, Progress, and Educational Purposes. Reprint of 1883 address., c. 1928 (Box 30)
  - Thomas Clark Atkeson. History of the Declaration of Purposes of the Grange. Address. Atlantic City, N.J., 1924 (Box 30)
  - Thomas Clark Atkeson. Outlines of Grange History. Washington, D.C.: The National Farm News., c. 1928 (Box 30)
  - Margaret H. Caldwell. Juvenile Handbook. National Grange. (Box 30)
  - Charles M. Gardner. 75th Anniversary Massachusetts State Grange., 1947 (Box 30)
    Historical Address given at the Diamond Jubilee Session of the Massachusetts State Grange.
  - Charles M. Gardner. The Grange - Friend of the Farmer, 1867-1947. Washington, D. C.: National Grange., 1949 (Box 30)
  - William Free Hill. A Brief History of the Grange Movement in Pennsylvania. Chambersburg, Pennsylvania: Pennsylvania Grange News., 1923 (Box 30)
  - Edward F. Holter. The Grange Builds - Grange Lecturer's Handbook and Lecturer's Projects., 1960-1961 (Box 30)
  - Edward F. Holter. Grange Lecturer's Handbook., 1960 (Box 30)
  - Guy B. Horton. Fifty Programs by lecturer of Vermont State Grange. Montpelier, Vermont., 1930 (Box 30)
  - Janet W. Hopkins. History of the Rhode Island State Grange., 1939 (Box 30)
    With biographies of past State Masters and Annals of Subordinate, Pomona, and Juvenile Granges.
  - Herschel D. Newsom. Address before the 97th [98th] Annual Session of the National Grange. Atlantic City, N.J., Nov. 9, 1964 (Box 30)
  - Herschel D. Newsom. Address before the 102nd Annual Session of the National Grange. Peoria, Illinois., Nov. 11, 1968 (Box 30)
  - Edward Winslow Martin. History of the Grange Movement; or the Farmer's War Against Monopolies. Chicago: National Publishing Co., 1874 (Box 30)
  - Alpha Messer. The Grange. Its Advantages. What It Has Accomplished. What It Hopes to Accomplish. Organization of Granges. Declaration of Purposes. Washington: The National Grange., c. 1895 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Building the Grange and a Growing Service Program, 1867-1944. Springfield, Mass: National Grange Publicity Bureau. (Box 30)
  - Building the Grange and a Growing Service Program, 1867-1946. Springfield, Mass: National Grange Publicity Bureau. (Box 30)
  - Building the Grange and a Growing Service Program, 1867-1947. Springfield, Mass: National Grange Publicity Bureau. (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Grange. Centennial Edition., Nov. 1967 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Fifty-Fourth Annual Session. Massachusetts State Grange., 1920 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Fifty-Fifth Annual Session. Portland, Oregon., 1921 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Ninety-Fourth Annual Session. Winston-Salem, North Carolina. Baltimore, Maryland: The Waverly Press., 1960 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Ninety-Fifth Annual Session. Worcester, Massachusetts. Baltimore, Maryland: The Waverly Press., 1961 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Ninety-Sixth Annual Session. Fort Wayne, Indiana. Baltimore, Maryland: The Waverly Press., 1962 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Ninety-Seventh Annual Session. Portland, Oregon. Baltimore, Maryland: The Waverly Press., 1963 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Ninety-Eighth Annual Session. Atlantic City, New Jersey. Baltimore, Maryland: The Waverly Press., 1964 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... Ninety-Ninth Annual Session. Topeka, Kansas. Baltimore, Maryland: The Waverly Press., 1965 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... 100th Annual Session. Minneapolis, Minnesota. Kutztown, Pa.: D. H. Conover Printing Co., 1966
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... 101st Annual Session. Syracuse, New York. Kutztown, Pa.: D. H. Conover Printing Co., 1967 (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Metropolitan Past Masters Association. The Grange and its Achievements. Somerville, Massachusetts: Gage Printing Co., 1920 (Box 30)
  - National Grange, Summary of Legislative Policies and Programs., 1963 (Box 30)
  - National Grange, Summary of Legislative Policies and Programs., 1965 (Box 30)
  - National Grange, Summary of Legislative Policies and Programs., 1968 (Box 30)
  - National Grange, Summary of Legislative Policies and Programs., 1969 (Box 30)
  - New England Grange. New England - The Gibraltar of the Grange. A historical souvenir., 1938 (Box 30)
  - Stuart Noblin. The Grange in North Carolina 1929-1954: A Story of Agricultural Progress. Greensboro, North Carolina: The Piedmont Press. (Box 30)
  - Ohio State Grange Executive Committee. Golden Jubilee History. Ohio State Grange 1872-1922. Salem, Ohio: The Lyle Printing Co. (Box 30)
  - Ohio State Grange. Diamond Jubilee History. Ohio State Grange 1872-1947. (Box 30)
  - National Grange. Journal of Proceedings... 112th Annual Session. Denver, Colorado., 1978 (Box 30)
  - Jonathan Periam. The Groundswell: A History of the Origins, Aims, and Progress of the Farmers' Movement. Cincinatti: E. Hannaford & Co., 1874 (Box 30)
  - W. L. Robinson. The Grange's First Century of Service and Evolution, 1867-1967. Washtington, D.C.: The National Grange., 1966 (Box 30)
  - Ralph W. Smith. The History of the Iowa State Grange. Patrons of Husbandry from 1868 to 1946. Manchester, Iowa: Iowa State Grange. (Box 30)
  - State Historical Society of Iowa. The Palimpset, Iowa City., 1950 (Box 30)
- Series XII. National Grange Ribbons, Medals, Buttons
  - National Grange ribbons, emblems, 1892-1905 (Box 1)
  - National Grange Convention ribbons and medals, 1932-1941 (Box 1)
  - National Grange ribbons with medals, n.d., 1906 (Box 1)
  - National Grange state, national, lecturer convention ribbons with medals, 1907-1937 (Box 1)
  - National Grange state, national, lecturers, reunion and convention buttons and ribbons, 1903-1941 (Box 1)
  - National Grange ribbons and buttons, 1900-1915 (Box 1)
    From Olnay Senate, Ohio Dairymen's Association, A.A.F.I.W., Ohio Corn Improvement Association, K.S.O., F.F.A., Elyria, American Soybean Association.
- Series XIII. State Quarterly Reports
  - State Quarterly Reports, 1966-1974 (Box 32)
- Series XIV. National Quarterly Reports
  - National Quarterly Reports, 1968-1974 (Box 33)
  - National Quarterly Reports, 1964-1974 (Box 34)
  - National Quarterly Reports, 1964-1967 (Box 36)
- Series XV. Sixty Year Certificates
  - Sixty Year Certificates, n.d. (Box 35)
- Series XVI. Golden Sheaf Certificates
  - Golden Sheaf Certificates (Numbers 33,000 - 35,499), n.d. (Box 37)
  - Golden Sheaf Certificates (Numbers 35,500 - 37,999), n.d. (Box 38)
  - Golden Sheaf Certificates (Numbers 38,000 - 39,747), n.d. (Box 39)
- Series XVII. Herschel D. Newsom
  - Herschel D. Newsom testimonies, speeches, etc., 1958-1962 (Box 40)
- Series XVIII. Peace Corps - Guatemala
  - Peace Corps - Guatemala, 1960s (Box 41)
- Series XIX. Consultant - Charles Bowling
  - Consultant - Charles Bowling, n.d. (Box 44)
  - Consultant - Charles Bowling, n.d. (Box 45)
- Series XX. Youth Department
  - Youth Department - Wib Justi, n.d. (Box 42)
  - Youth Department - Wib Justi, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Youth Department, n.d. (Box 45)
  - Youth Department International Program, n.d. (Box 46)
- Series XXI. H. L. Graham Files
  - H. L. Graham files (A - Gatt), 1963-1968 (Box 47)
  - H. L. Graham files (Gr - Pop), 1963-1968 (Box 48)
  - H. L. Graham files (Pot - Soi), 1963-1968 (Box 49)
  - H. L. Graham files (St - Wo), 1963-1968 (Box 50)
  - H. L. Graham Correspondence files (by state) (Box 50)
- Series XXII. Miscellaneous Transportation (and Trade)
  - Miscellaneous transportation (and trade), 1959-1971 (Box 51)
- Series XXIII. Commodity and Dairy Files
  - Commodity and Dairy Files, 1959-1968 (Box 52)
  - Commodity and Dairy Files, 1959-1968 (Box 53)
- Series XXIV. National Legislative Files
  - National legislative files (A - Col), 1963-1968 (Box 54)
  - National legislative files (Cot - El), 1963-1968 (Box 55)
  - National legislative files (Em - Foo), 1963-1968 (Box 56)
  - National legislative files (For - Rec), 1963-1968 (Box 57)
  - National legislative files (Red - Wes), 1963-1968 (Box 58)
  - National legislative files (Wh-Yo), 1963-1968 (Box 59)
  - National legislative files (A - Fai), 1969-1970 (Box 60)
  - National legislative files (Fam - Farmer Bill), 1969-1970 (Box 61)
  - National legislative files (Farmer Bill - Pos), 1969-1970 (Box 62)
  - National legislative files (Pot - Tax loss), 1969-1970 (Box 63)
  - National legislative files (Tax reform - Wh), 1969-1970 (Box 64)
- Series XXV. Miscellaneous
  - New England Lecturers Conference (Box 65)
  - Mid-Atlantic Leaders Conference, 1968 (Box 65)
  - Conferences - Press (Box 65)
  - Conferences, 1968 (Box 65)
  - Conferences, 1976 (Box 65)
  - Deputy Conference Ideas (Box 65)
  - CPP, 1963 (Box 65)
  - CPP, 1966-1967 (Box 65)
  - CPP Correspondence (Box 65)
  - Commodity Groups (Box 65)
  - Committees - Intersession (Box 65)
  - Citation, 1960 (Box 65)
  - Committees, 1965-1966 (Box 65)
  - Committee Congress (Box 65)
  - Roy Battles (Box 65)
  - Annual Session, 1964 (Box 65)
  - Annual Session, 1965 (Box 65)
  - Annual Session, 1965 (Box 65)
  - Annual Session, 1981 (Box 65)
  - Annual Session - Pictures (Box 65)
  - Milton Fitch - Centennial Promotion (Box 65)
  - Estabrook Address - Kansas (Box 65)
  - Debt Retirement (Box 65)
  - "The Reporter" (Box 65)
  - Plan and Outline (Box 65)
  - Membership Certificate Awards (Box 65)
  - National Grange Monthly File (Box 65)
  - Noblin Report (Misc.) (Box 65)
  - National Wool Growers (Box 65)
  - New England Homestead (Box 65)
  - National Grange Monthly (Box 65)
  - Monthly Subscription File (Box 65)
  - Inquiries re: Membership National Grange (Box 65)
  - Membership Certificate Awards (Box 65)
  - Mailings and Distribution List (Box 65)
  - Legislative Mailing (Box 65)
  - Mailing List - Ray Taylor, 1968 (Box 65)
  - Mailing Lists (Special Publications, etc.) (Box 65)
  - Legal & Economic Influence of the Grange (Box 65)
  - Legislative Committee (Box 65)
  - Legislative Report (Box 65)
  - Kiplinger Letter (Box 66)
  - Mailing - State Masters & National Officers (Box 66)
  - Index Files - BN (Box 66)
  - Guinea - Marshall (Box 66)
  - Gun Control (Box 66)
  - Hall, Cliff (Box 66)
  - Grange Letter, 1960-1961 (Box 66)
  - Grange P.R. Letters (Box 66)
  - Grange Magazine and Mailing List (Box 66)
  - Grange Publications (Box 66)
  - Don Diddle (Box 66)
  - Booster Night (Box 66)
  - Dairy (Box 66)
  - Cost Allocation (Box 66)
  - Council for Economic Growth & Security (Box 66)
  - Congressmen's Letters & Replies from S/M's (Box 66)
  - Grange Members in Congress (Box 66)
  - Contributions (Box 66)
  - Convention Handbook (Box 66)
  - Fair Display (Old) (Box 66)
  - Domestic Parity Leaflet (Box 66)
  - Deputies (letters to) (Box 66)
  - Deputies (Box 66)
  - Regional Conferences, 1957-1968 (Box 66)
  - Regional Conferences (Box 66)
  - Grange Leaders Conferences (Box 66)
  - Lecturers Conferences (Box 66)
  - 121 Annual Convention, 1987 (Box 66)
  - Legislative summaries (Box 67-70)
  - Membership statistical records, 1921-1975 (Box 67-70)
  - Herschel D. Newsom speeches, 1951-1965 (Box 67-70)
  - Testimonies (Box 67-70)
  - Financial records (Box 67-70)
  - The National Grange Monthly, 1962 (Box 67-70)
  - "Why Farmers are in the Red" poster, c.1938 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - 1 reel neg. microfilm